

" With great power...comes great responsibility "

Stan Lee

Writer | Editor | Publisher | Producer
Marvel Comics

Suman Kanti Roy

- ★ Kolkata, West Bengal
- roy.sumankanti@gmail.com
- +91 7411940354
- https://s-kroy.github.io/ux/

Tech Expertise

0 0 • Adobe Experience Design 0 0 • Adobe Photoshop 0 0 • Adobe Illustrator 0 0 Adobe After Effects 0 0 • Adobe InDesign OO Basic html-5 and css-3 OO Basic Javascript, Bootstrap 0 0 0 Microsoft Visual Studio Microsoft Power BI OO BeginnerIntermediateAdvanced





Ethnographic Cognitive **Empathy** Persona Wireframe & **Analysis** Prototype Design Strategy & **Thinking Planning Usability** Interface & **Evaluation** Interaction Design **UX** Agile Workshop **Activities** Approach Skills **UX Audits Technical** Review Writing **UX Team** Taxonomy Leadership Mapping **UX Product** Quantitative Branding Case Study

Information

Architecture

UX Design

Documenting

Professional Profile

As creative professional, I love to paint on canvas and digital surface. I do both User Experience Design and User Interface Design for interactive digital product and enterprise application solutions. In-short I am connecting dotbetween human vision with machine algorithm. I have diversified experience across multiple domains. I have worked new start-up as well leading corporate brands with excellency.

Academic Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts Govt. College of Art & Craft, Agartala Subject: Painting | 2006 - 2010

Bachelor of Science Maharaja Bir Bikram College, Agartala Subject: Mathematics I 2004 - 2006

Employment History

17 Jan 2022 — today's date **Lexmark International Inc.** Usability Design Engineer

17 Mar 2017 — 15 Jan 2022

Wipro Technologies Limited

Senior UI & UX Designer

11 Mar 2015 — 15 Mar 2017

RxPrism Health Systems Pvt. Ltd.

Creative UI & UX Designer

06 Jan 2014 — 20 Feb 2015 **Hibu India Private Limited**Graphic & Web Designer

15 Apr 2013 — 30 Dec 2013

Bid & Hammer Fine Art Auctioneer

Visual Designer & Researcher

Course & Certification

- Adobe UX Foundation Learning Journey Badge Powered by Edcast
- XD Essentials Assessment and Training Issued by Adobe on Credly
- Certificate of Completion on HTML, CSS Including SASS by Udemy
- Certificate of Completion on Bootstrap-4 From Scratch by Udemy

Reward & Recognition

- Earned digital badge on "Adobe UX Foundation Learning Journey" from NASSCOM Futureskills platform powered by EdCast.
- TopGear challenge achievement award for official selection "SMC Digital Security" in 2019 from Wipro Digital.
- "Cash Rewards of \$100 gift" & recognition with digital badge after successfully completed assignment of Adobe XD Essentials.
- Appreciation form "Bengali Movie Director Atanu Ghosh" for creating official logo of Satyajit Ray Film Society Bengaluru in 2017.
- Win "Best Creative Professional Award in 2015" organised by Rxprism Health System Pvt. Ltd. in World Environment Day.
- "Sumangol Sen Memorial Scholarship" for painting category from Govt. College of Arts and Craft, Agartala, Tripura in 2010.